Nicole Brinza

951 S Fern Ave, Elmhurst, IL, 60126 (224) 256-9068 ionela.brinza@yahoo.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Hard-working professional with 11+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of event management, market research, sales, marketing, web development and office administration. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the role at your company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MOSAIC CLAIMS MANAGEMENT, Houston, TX (work remotely) Project Manager, Oct 2021 – Present

- Ensure a positive and high-quality customer experience through all interactions
- Focus on continuous improvement in project delivery
- Work closely with the CEO to identify, plan, organize and drive activities related to marketing projects
- Manage insurance claims related projects
- · Create the website of the company; in charge of Digital Marketing campaigns
- Intake leads info and manage the CRM (oversee the workflow)

AAA LOSS CONSULTING, Rolling Meadows, IL

Director of Operations, Sep 2020 - September 2021

- Work with the HR department to create job descriptions, hire competent personnel and oversee employee training programs
- Keep track of the company's revenue margins and conduct budget reviews to maximize profits
- Oversee client support services and materials and inventory management
- Ensure operational activities remain on time and within a defined budget
- Create the website of the company and manage social media activity
- Be in charge of the marketing campaigns

GENESIS MARKETING CORPORATION, Forrest Park, IL Corporate trainer/Team Lead, Oct 2019 – Aug 2020

- Participate in daily meetings to go over sales strategies and team progress towards consulting goals
- Predict client behavior by researching market-specific changes and reaching out to clients affected by the changes, as well as confluent resolution for any clients experiencing difficulties
- Coaching newer team members on completing a consultation using impulse factors, key steps to a critical conversation and get great work habits
- Write, edit and deliver speeches to ameliorate the training process
- Plan and direct staffing, training, and performance evaluations to develop and control sales and service programs

EGOSEM CONSULTING INC, Towson, MD

Marketing Account Manager, Nov 2017 – Sep 2019

- Resolve customer complaints regarding sales and service.
- Monitor customer preferences to determine focus of sales efforts.
- Review operational records and reports to project sales and determine profitability.
- Confer or consult with department heads to plan advertising services and to secure information on equipment and customer specifications.
- Track consumer retention and purchase trends to contribute to the marketing strategy of the company by using tools suck as the MIS Cloud Software

GENESIS MARKETING CORPORATION, Chicago, IL Marketing Account Manager, Jul 2017 – Nov 2017

- Determine price schedules and discount rates.
- Prepare and execute a sales and consulting pitch to clients affected by market-specific changes and adjusting pitch based on client responsiveness
- Plan and prepare advertising and promotional material to increase sales of products or services, working with customers, company officials, sales departments and advertising agencies.
- Gather and organize information to plan advertising campaigns.
- Become familiar with the structure of the business and different stages of growth towards growth project management (account management, corporate training, team management)

INTERNET MARKETING ONLINE, Timisoara, Timis Communication and Public Relations Specialist, Sep 2011 – Jun 2014

- Respond to requests for information from the media or designate an appropriate spokesperson or information source.
- Establish or maintain cooperative relationships with representatives of community, consumer, employee, or public interest groups.
- Plan or conduct market or public opinion research to test products or determine potential for product success, communicating results to client or management.
- Develop marketing campaigns for environmental technologies or services.

EDUCATION

Politehnica University of Timisoara Timisoara, Timis, Romania

Master of Communication and Digital Media Communication (Jun 2013)

Politehnica University of Timisoara Timisoara, Timis, Romania

Bachelor of Public Relations Communication (Jun 2011)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Romanian Business level Speaking, Reading, Writing
- Spanish Business level Speaking, Reading, Writing
- Customer Acquisition
- Social Media Marketing (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, html, Wix, CRM)
- Public Relations
- Customer Service
- Sales and Marketing

CREDENTIALS AND LICENSES

- Certified in Small Business (2016, Chicago, IL)
- Certified in Sales and Marketing (2017, Chicago, IL)
- Certified in Customer Service (2018, Chicago, IL)
- Certificate in Front-End Development (enrolled student, will graduate in April)